Modestas Kairys

Frontend Software Engineer



ABOUT ME

I specialize in frontend, but someday I want to become good enough to be called an all-round developer.

I think my colleagues would describe me as someone who takes initiative, easy to work with, and a diligent worker.

The things I value most about programming is probably predictability and stability. If something is wrong with your code, then it's a 99.9% probability that you did something wrong. I feel like you rarely can find that in other lines of work and I'm happy to call myself a software developer.

EXPERIENCE

UAB Amidus, Vilnius — Junior Software Engineer

April 2016 - May 2017

My first real job right before graduating university. My main responsibilities included writing backend services on .NET, various scripting tasks using PowerShell, and filling out documentations.

Danske Bank, Vilnius — *Software Engineer*

August 2017 - July 2019

Main work tool was a platform called BPM made by IBM. It relied on vanilla JavaScript to produce a full solution for the bank's internal system.

Telia, Vilnius — *Software Engineer*

December 2021 - Present

After coming back from Japan, I was eager to work with a modern JS framework. Since I had encountered React before, in Amidus, I decided to give it a go. Telia has a wide tech stack, so I'm learning something new everyday. Currently my focus is on code efficiency, to get better at TypeScript, and I want to pick up NextJS in the near future.

EDUCATION

Užupio gimnazija, Vilnius

2008 - 2012

Vilnius University, Vilnius — Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering

2012 - 2016

SKILLS

Javascript	****
HTML	****
JSON	****
XML	****
CSS	☆ ★★★★
React	☆ ★★★★
TypeScript	☆☆★★★
Git	☆☆★★★
Node.js	☆☆★★★
Scrum	☆☆★★★
Splunk	☆☆☆★★
Java	☆☆☆☆★
.NET	☆☆☆☆★

LANGUAGES

Lithuanian - mother tongue

English - daily use

Japanese - survivable

CONTACTS

Address: Viršupio sodu 21-oji g.

8, Vilnius, 10230 Mob.: +37067072506

Email: mo.kairys@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/modestas-kai

rys-64965b134/